Guide to the Juan Felipe Herrera Papers, ca. 1970-1998 M1043
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series 1: Correspondence
  - Powers, Thomas L. Letter from Thomas L. Powers, Flint Public Library, regarding itinerary for visit. 8/31/93. with flyer and itinerary. (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Press, Toni. Letter from Toni Press, playwright, 6/24/90. (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Pyle, Charles. Letter from Charles Pyle, attorney regarding Romero v. Herrera. 6/4/96 [1] (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Pyle, Charles. Letter from Charles Pyle, attorney, regarding settlement of Romero v. Herrera. 9/25/97 With xerox of notarized release from JFH. [2] (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Quinn, Tom. Fax letter from Tom Quinn (Private Investigator) regarding news clips on education. Fresno, Ca. 5/18/98 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Quintana, Alvina. My mother's memorial poem memento, Maria Garcia. A letter from my cousin Alvina Quintana, re: my mother's passing. 8/21/86 and last letter from my Aunt Aurelia Quintana, uncle Fernando Guzman. /Xmas card: 12/6/88. [1] (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Quintana, Alvina. cousin & professor 1/5/93 [2] (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Quintana, Alvina. Invitation Letter. Latino Literary Voices and Proposal. 6 pages. [3] 1/14/98 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Quintana, Leroy. poet, 2/9/93 [1] (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Quintana, Leroy. Letter from Leroy Quintana, poet, editor. 3/1/93. [to Margarita (Luna Robles?)] [2] (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Quintana, Leroy. (to Margarita Luna Robles), San Diego Mesa College. 4/20/ 93. [3] (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Quintana, Vicente. Letter: from my cousin Vicente Quintana. from San Quentin-CrF. 5/4/78. [1] (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Quintana, Vicente. Five Letters from my cousin Vicente Quintana in San Quentin and CCF­Soledad, Late seventies to early eighties. Plus visitor approval pass. [2] (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Quintana, Vicente, Cousin. 2 page letter. 7/10/84. (From CTF­Soledad) [3] (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Quintana, Vicente. Letter from my cousin Vicente Quintana from CIT-Soledad. 6/20/86. (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Reed, Ishmael. Letter from Ishmael Reed to contribute to essay anthology. 7/25/94. [1] (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Reed, Ishmael. Contract for essay to be included in anthology, Cutural Wars, Cultural Peace. With note by Ishmael Reed. 1/3/96. [2] (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Reyes, Sarah. Hispanic Chamber of Commerce. 9/9/97. Fresno, Guest Speaker. (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Reynolds, Jolene. Letters from Students: Matt Wilkins, poet (8/9/90) and Jolene Reynolds (visual artist/ 6/2/90) former students in my undergrad writing workshop at Univ of Iowa. (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Ricardo-Livingstone, Rod. Student, Poet-Letter, 2 pages and 6 poems. 6/1/98 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - River Styx. Notice from River Styx journal regarding acceptance of poetry. 7/31/90. (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Rivero, Perry. Fax: thank you letter from Penny Rivero, Principal at Campus Park Elementary school. 4/6/98. (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Robinson, Lynda. 7/6/ 98. Thank you letter. Elementary Partnership Program, CSUF. (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Robles, Kimberly. Excerpts on Jim Sagel's death (Friend, poet, writer). Various newspapers. Note from Librarian, Kimberly Robles. 4/98. 11 pages. (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Roca, Omar. Letter from Omar Roca, from Curbstone Press, regarding reading tour. 10 pages. 8/23/ 95. (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Roche, Judith. Letter from Judith Roche, regarding Bumbershoot festival panels 6/24/92.2 pages. (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Rocio Magana, Maria. Letter. ASI-CSIJF Teatro Award. 8/29/97.1 page. (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Rodriguez, Luis J. Letter from Luis J. Rodriguez, writer. Regarding readings, European tour. 10/29/91. 3 pages. [1] (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Rodriguez, Luis J. Letter from Luis J. Rodriguez, writer, reagrding Paris Conference. With other materials. 4 pages. 10/10/94. [2] (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Rodriguez, Rosamaria. Letter from Rosamaria Rodriguez, regarding inclusion in anthology. UC Berkeley. 6/24/92 (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - Rodriguez, Steve. Tulare County Reading Council Presentation Confirmation Form, 12/18/95. (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - Rohmer, Harriet. Publisher Children's Book Press; San Francisco; 6 pages; Comments! Edits for Upside Down Boy, 1/5/97. (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - Romo, Tere. Letter from Tere Romo regarding panel for CAC. 1/21/92. (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - Rosenman, Jane. Letter to Jane Rosenman, editor at Washington Square Press, NYC. 10/3/90. 2 pp. (Box 6, Folder 53)
  - Roth, Margaret Ann. Letter from Margaret Ann Roth, editor, Boston Review. 10/17/90 (Box 6, Folder 54)
  - Ryan, Carol. Letter from Carol Ryan, my ex-first-wife, regarding money for children. 9/9/95. (Box 6, Folder 55)
  - Ryan, Joaquin. Letter and Xeroxed Fotos from my son Joaquin Ryan. 6/24/97. (Box 6, Folder 56)
  - Ryan, Joshua. Postcard from my son Joshua Ryan. 2/6/90. (Box 6, Folder 57)
  - Ryan, Joshua. Postcard from my son, Joshua Ryan. 2/14/97. (Box 6, Folder 58)
  - Ryan, Marian. editor, Harcourt Brace, 12/11/95 & 1/24/96 (manuscripts). 7 pp. [1] (Box 6, Folder 59)
  - Ryan, Marian. 7/1/97. Marian Ryan. Hancourt Brace. 1 page. [2] (Box 6, Folder 60)
  - Ryan, Marilyn. Letter from Marilyn Ryan. director, CAC. Regarding Margarita Luna Robles. 11/6/84. (Box 6, Folder 61)
  - Sadler, Cathy. EMG Satellite Programs. 7/13/98. 4 pages. (Box 6, Folder 62)
  - Saenz, Benjamin Alire. Vita with photo, 1994. (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Sagel, Jim. Letter from Jim Sagel regarding reading in Fresno. 5/7/91. [1] (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Sagel, Jim. Two letters from Jim Sagel. poet, writer, 7/21/91, 7/18/94. [2] (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Sagel, Jim. Letter from Jim Sagel after visiting Fresno. 11/30/ 91. [3] (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Sagel, Jim. Acceptance form for Puerto del Sol, New Mexico State University publication, 1991[?] [4] (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Sagel, Jim. Photo for possible readings in Fresno, 1/20/94 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Sagel, Jim. 6/20/94 2p [5] (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Saldate, Macario. Letter from Macario Saldate regarding NACCS conference proposal. 3/29/91. (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Salinas, Ricardo. Letter from Ricardo "Slic Ric" Salinas (Culture Clash, actor) regarding our times together in El Teatro Campesino. Luis Valdez. 7/18/95. (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Schaefer, August. 2 Letters from August Schaefer, producer regarding Bisbee Poetry Festival. 2/11/92 2 pp.; 3/8/92, 2 pp. (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Schmidt, Kyron. Xerox letter from Kyron Schmidt, regarding$5,000. award for Summer Arts. 12/22/94. Wells Fargo Bank Trust. Poetry into Performance workshop. (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Schneider, Richard. Contract from Richard Schneider to teach in Vermont College, 12/20/94. MFA Creative Writing Program. (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Schuster, Cindy. Letter from Cindy Schuster, editor of Compost. 12/8/96. (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Segura, Robert. Returned unopened letter with graduation notice and invitation of my step son's graduation (Robert Segura) from Clovis West high school to his cousin Yvette Melendez. 5/27/98. (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Serna, Elias. Letter from Elias Serna, Poet and Comedian. Poetry and short stories developed in Cherrie Moraga's class. 2/21/91. 14 pages. (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Serna, Laura. Assistant for June Jordan, poet. 1/30/95 (Fax) (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Sharrard, Bob. Letter from Bob Sharrard regarding contract for Mayan Drifter (enclosed) 9/7/94. (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Sherrill, Marjorie. Letter from Marjorie Sherrill, U of Az. 8/3/94 (Night Train), Book contract, 12/16/93. Two reviews of Ms. (formerly Zoo Suit on a Bed of Spanish Rice) 5p. 7/9/93. [1] (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Sherrill, Marjorie. Letter from Marjorie Sherrill, U of Az. press, regarding reading in San Francisco. Night Train to Tuxlta. 8/10/94. [2] (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Simba, Malik. Memo from Malik Simba regarding talk at Ethnic Studies Conference. 3/18/98 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Simmons, Elly. Letter. From Elly Simmons, artist for Calling the Doves (my first Childrens book). 6/27/94. (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Skeen, Sigrid. Receipt for visiting author payment, Woodlake Union School District, 3/29/96. (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Sklar, Morty. letter on my writing, 11/21/91 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Soldofsky, Alan. Letter of inviation to particpate in Summer Arts as Guest Artist. From Alan Saldofsky. 11/23/90 with 2 pages of info. (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Soto, Gary. Letter from Gary Soto. 11/14/91. (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Spalding, Jim Letter from Jim Spalding, CSU-Summer Arts, 5/12/97. (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Stern, Gerald. Two Letters from Gerald Stern, poet & Professor, re: poetry submitted. 8/20/90. (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Stimac, Richard C. [Editor, Tornado Alley, regarding JFH contribution to first issue, 1/2/91] (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Stone, Charlottle. Letter from Charlotte Stone, associate editor, Chronicle Books, SF. 11/14/94. (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Storace, Patricia. Note. The Paris Review. Poetry Contest. Patricia Storace, editor. 10/6/90. (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Surabian, Carol, TUCATE [Tucate County Association of Teachers of English. Annual Writer's in Training Conference. 4/16/98 (w/ MLR letter) (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Sutton, Pam Sutton. American Poetry Review, 9/25/92 (galleys), 4 pp. (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Szuter, Christine R. Editor in Chief. University of Arizona Press 2/16/98 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Tarango, Cristina. "Meet the Authors" Invitation. From Cristina Tarango at the Children's Books Press. SF. 4/8/98. (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Tatum, Charles. Acceptance contract for poem, from Charles Tatum, Univ. Az. 11/20/90. (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Tatum, Charles. Letter from Charles Tatum, regarding inclusion in anthology. U of Az. 3/4/92. (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Tello, Maria. Casa Hispana de Bellas Artes, Re: Literary history, 2p. SF, 11/5/82 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Temple University Press. Royalty contract [for Mayan Drifter] 1/4/96. Advance payments. 3 pages. (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Temple University Press. Various letters from Temple University Press. 1996-97. Regarding Mayan Drifter. 20p. (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Temple University Press. Reviews of Book proposal, Cilantro Facials, 6/25/97 (letter and Fax) (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Thompson, Bill. Briarwood Writers' Alliance, letter regarding flight information, Aug. 26, 1993. (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Thompson, Jan. letter regarding advance copies of Night Train to Tuxtla, Univ. of Arizona Press, 10/26/94; 2) pages with ads for same book. 3) Fax of reviews for same book, 2p. [move to corresp.] (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - Tien, Chang-Lin. Letter from Chancellor Chang-Lin Tien, UC Berkeley. 6/14/96. Regents Fellowship. (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - Tortolero, Carlos. Letter from Carlos Tortolero and Carlos Cumpian, on Nezahualcoyotl Festival. 12/10/90. [1] (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - Tortolero, Carlos. Letter from Carlos Tortolero, re: Nezahualcoyotl Poetry Festival. 4/23/91. 2 pages. [2] (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - Troike, Rudolph. Letter. Notice of Short List for Univ. Arizona position. Dept. English. Rudolph Troike. 3/12/90. (Box 7, Folder 46)
  - Trueblood, Kate. Letter from Kate Trueblood of Before Columbus Fondation regarding publication of work. 10/24/90. (Box 7, Folder 47)
  - University of Arizona Press. Six letter from University of AZ. Press regarding Night train to Tuxtla. 1993-94. (Box 7, Folder 48)
  - University of Arizona Press. Contract for Outside Tibet (Border-Crosser with a Lamborghini Dream). 2/23/98. 6 pages Xerox. (Box 7, Folder 49)
  - University of Iowa Press. Letter. Notice of receipt of poetry ms. for Iowa Poetry Prize. 4/4/90. (Box 7, Folder 50)
  - Urrea, Luis. Letter from Luis Urrea. Writer. 3/1/92. (Box 7, Folder 51)
  - Vailakis, Yvonne Gordon. UC-Irvine, 2nd place Chicano Literary Contest, 5/4/85 (Box 7, Folder 52)
  - Valdez, Patsi. Copy of art release from to Pattsi Valdez, with letter. 7/4/96 (Box 7, Folder 53)
  - VandeStadt, Tom. Letter from Tom VandeStadt, assistant editor. American Anthropologist. Re: review. 2/26/97. (Box 7, Folder 54)
  - Vega, Robert. Robert Vega. Letter. CSUF. 10/28/97 3 pages. (Box 7, Folder 55)
  - Verke, Paul. Letter from Paul Verke, regarding service on the literature panel. California Arts Council. 4/7/93. 5 pages. [1] (Box 7, Folder 56)
  - Verke, Paul. Letter from Paul Verke of California Arts Council, regarding literature panel. 6/30/93. 3 pages. [2] (Box 7, Folder 57)
  - Villa, Raul. Letter from Raul Villa. Reading at Reed College. 10/9/91. [1] (Box 7, Folder 58)
  - Villa, Raul. literary critic, professor. postcard 11/91. [2] (Box 7, Folder 59)
  - Villa, Raul H. Occidental College 5/19/98. Poetry Release for Barrio-Logos; 2 pages. xerox letter. (Box 7, Folder 60)
  - Villatore, Linda. Letter from Linda Villatorre regarding video project. 6/30/94 (Box 7, Folder 61)
  - Vogelsang, Arthur. Poetry acceptance letter from Arthur Vogelsang poet and editor, American Poetry Review. 11/20/90. [1] (Box 7, Folder 62)
  - Vogelsang, Arthur. Letter of acceptance of poems from Arthur Vogelsang, American Poetry Review. 2/15/91. (Box 7, Folder 63)
  - Wall, Claire Marie. Letter from Claire Marie Wall regarding participation in the Young Writers Conference. 3/4/91. (Box 7, Folder 64)
  - Wallace, Lila. Five residency contracts for the Intersection for the Arts Poetrynational Touring Fellowship, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Warner, Sterling. Fax from Professor Sterling Warner (Evergreen Valley College), regarding permission to use poem, "Inside the Jacket." 9/26/95. 3 pages. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Watkins, Patrick. Letter from Patrick Watkins (deceased), director Summer Arts, to JFH, Regarding job changes. 6/29/94 [1] (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Watkins, Patrick. (last letter from him), 8/22/94 (Summer Arts-CSU) [2] (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Weissman, Benjamin. Letter from Benjamin Weissman, regarding support for Beyond Baroque Lit Center. 6/6/92. (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Wilkins, Matt. Letter from Matt Wilkins, student, poet. 2/6/92 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Williams, John Taylor. Palmer & Dodge Agency. Boston 1 page. 8/4/97. (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Williams, Russell Ben. Editor. Arte Public Press. Contract Letter. 7/28/98. (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Wirth, John. Letter of support for travel project from John Wirth, director of Center for Latin American Studies. 6/6/78. Stanford. (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Wulftange, Margarita. Letter from Margarita Wulftange, teacher, and 8 letters from students at Barnes Elementary. 6/12/98. (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Ybarra, Lea. Memo from Dr. Lea Ybarra to Dr. Peter J. Klassen, Dean, regarding release time from JFH. CSU-Fresno. 11/9/90. [1] (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Ybarra, Lea. Letter from Dr. Lea Ybarra regarding presentation to students. 2/5/91. CSUFresno. [2] (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Yurman, Rich. Poet, Letter, SF. 8/5/86. (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Zelwer, Barbara; Psychologist, Mexican Political Asylum. 9/25/97. (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Zimmer, Paul. Two letters from Paul Zimmer, Director of the University of Iowa Press. Regarding Mayan Drifter Ms. 6/2/94, 6/23/94. with envelope. (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Zuckerman, Linda. Letter from Linda Zuckerman, editor/Harcourt Brace, regarding stories. 4/22/98. (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence [1]: Nine [ten] letters from various poets & writers met at the Breadloaf Writers Conference. 1990, with envelopes. [Biancho, J.W. (photographs); Burton, Elizabeth A.; Furbish, Matthew; Klam, Matt; Leach, Tim; Spence, Michael, and Hashimoto, Sharon; Solheim, Jim and Joyce; 3 others unidentified] (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence [2]: Four letters regarding Mission District Latina/o Literary Project. (JFH). 1991. [Ellington, Sushanna; Hellyer, Paul; Silver, Mae; Thompson, John] (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence [3]: Fifteen xeroxed letters, misc. 1990-91. [Alarcon, Francisco X. (UC Santa Cruz); Antell, Nancy (Rohwedder); Stephen Berg, et al (American Poetry Review); Canales, Maricarmen (Feria Internacional); Gonzalez, Ray (Guadalupe Arts Center, 2 letters); Hummer, T.R. (New England Review); Knauss, Carol (Middlebury College); McIlvoy, Kevin (Puerto del Sol); Patterson, Martha (Iowa Journal of Literary Studies); Sklar, Morty (The Spirit That Moves Us Press); Tatum, Charles (University of Arizona); Vogelsang, Arthur (American Poetry Review); Trina[?] (CSU Fresno); Conference Program 10/30/91. (Box 8, Folder 19)
- Series 2: Manuscripts, Journals and Other Literary Material
  - Subseries 1: Manuscripts, Drafts, and Notes
    - Cielorojo mi corazon verde 1972-1974 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Approximately 50 loose poems, drafts, teatro sketches, notes and short stories written since 1974. (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Flama de Luz / serie de cantos para la exposicion xicanarte 1975 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Green - 1978 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Sketch Pad: drawings, notes. 4x6. 24sheets. 2/9/79. (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Sketchpad. Late 1970's. Notes. 24 pp. torn. (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - "Linro Amarillo" Transit Notebook.10/20/80. Thoughts on Culture, performance & Field Notes on Chicano events. 60 pp. (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - EL LUCKY. 3x5. Notebook. 5/13/81. Interview with Steve Oropeza [San Francisco Mime Troupe], in Seattle Washington: On Performance, notes. 50 pp. (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - 3 x 5 Notebook. 5/23/81. 50 sheets. Notes, questions, addresses (with M L Rob1es "Te Quiero" on back). (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Euquerovoni. 5x8 100 sheet. Sketchpad. Notes & Drawings. 12/27/81. (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Nuevas Notas en verde. Sketch pad. 5x8. 6/82. Poems, notes, drawings. loop. (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Notes for "Sound, Rhythm & Pattern" writing workshop held in San Jose Ca. 8/21/82. (One of the early meetings with Poetry collective, Florisong & with Margarita Luna Robles, the director 2p (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Night Train to Veracruz. Draft, 12 pages, 7/26/83, SF. Ca. (forerunner to Night Train to Tuxtla poem in 1993). (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Beleza, draft unpub poem, 8/27/83 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Papaya. Original music (Jorge Lujan, Mexico) set to "Papaya" poem by JFH. Early 80's. (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Untitled poem from early 80's. 4 p. JFH. (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Aquabee all purpose sketchbook. 30p. Notes, outlines & letters. (to Yvonne Yarbro-Bejarano, lit critic, ex-wife). early 80's. (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Notas de Ondas. 9/30/82. /Notebook: sketches, notes, drawings, 20 pp. Seattle, Wa. (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - "Representacion e invención cultural: Poesia chicana. Essay for La Opinion. Chicano Poetry Issue. Los Angeles. Early 80's. By Francisco X. A!arcon an Juan Felipe Herrera. 15 pages typed. Plus 4 pages of bios of authors. (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - 1983-84. SALE Poems & Notes. 6x8 sketch pad. 20 pp. (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Night Train to Veracruz. Poem, various drafts1983 -1985. Typed and handwritten. 30 pages. (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - The Califas Movimiento 1964- 1984, article by JFH (Poetry Flash, 3/84)[incomplete] (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Article: The Henchman & The Critico: Maneuvering a "Minority Literature." 4 pp. (JFH). 1984. a part of Sin Chaketa ms. (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Sin Chaketa [1984] [1] (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Sin Chaketa [1984] [2] (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Florisong, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Ciclo Topacio/Sin Chaketa. 11/27/84. drawing pad. 24 sheets. Notes. (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - AC1 (anti-covers) 12-10-84 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - NPS. Notepad. Small. 3x2. 80 pp. Notes, poems w/collective poem by JFH, MLRobles & Francisco X. Alarcon. 3/18/85. SF.ca. (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Steno Notebook. Mexican God. 8/9//85. Draft for Facegames Poetry Book (1987 published). 6x9. 80 pp. (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - 12/22/85. Small notebook. Notes. 40 pp. (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Camouflage. 22 pp. (two versions). 1985. (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Literary Asylums. Two xeroxed and enlarged pages from the American Poetry Review. 1985. JFH poetry. (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Sestina: Field.. by JFH, 1985./only copy. (on mother's death). (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Margarita Rania Amor. 3x4 sketchpad. Notes & Drawings. 80 pp.mid 80's. (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - 255. Poem. mid-eighties. "Slenderness of my body." 2 pages. Handwritten. (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Translation of "'Slic Ric' Salinas Rapping on 24th" (JFH) by Jorge Herrera, poet and friend. For Broadside series: Toma Chocolate #1. 1/986. (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - The Book of Juan; Notes, Diaries. Perforated Index cards Book. 3x5. 9/30/86. (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Gato's LineC: Pass Laws Revisited. Written for Humanizarte, San Francisco, CA, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Notebook Rhodia: 2/4/88. notes. 80 pp. (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - 2/25/88. Poems & Notes. incomplete. 30 pp. (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - "Planet & Eyes: History and Perception in the Printmaking of Emmanuel C. Montoya" essay (JFH). Gallery opening brochure. Chicago. 6/5/88. (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Rhodia Notebook. 11/88. entries and notes. Iowa City, IA. 40 pp. (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Everything Must Change. Poem. 1 p. 1988. (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Half-a-Boot of Italy 1988 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Dreamboxer. Notes for Dreamboxer One-Man Show. Comedy, poetry, monologues, multi-media. At the City Lights Theatre, San Jose, Ca. 11 pp. 1988. (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Open Air. Poem. 2 p. 1988. (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Small Pad. When I Was In Manhattan (First draft for "Binoculars poem" Univ. of IA. 1988. 20 pp. (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Expose Me - Notes 1-11-89 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Ear Cassette. Pocket Sketch Book. 3/14/89. 80 pp. Drawings & Notes. (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Something Tropical (Days of Invasion). 15 pp. Summer, 1989. (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Mural of the Innocent. 58 pp. Play. Iowa Playwritghts Workshop. Univ. of Iowa. Staged Reading. 10/14/89. (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Prison Journal. 30 pp. Iowa Playwritghts Workshop. Univ. of Iowa. Staged Reading, 11/19/89 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Arrivals, Accordians and reversible explanations - 12-8-89 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Free the Living find the dead (Performance Project on index cards) 1989 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Training - by Matthew Saul Lippman - 1989 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Workshop folder - University of Iowa 1989, 99 pp (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Writing workshop poetry - Collection - 1989 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - [University of Iowa Writer's Workshop spiral bound notebook, ca. 1989] (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - 6 Loose Poems -1989 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Days of Invasion -1989 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - "Chicano Literature in an Almond Shell." Notes on Chicano literature for a workshop in Marvin Bell's workshop at the Iowa Wrtiers Workshop. U of Iowa 1989 2p (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Iowa Writer's Workshop - worksheet pieces 1989-1990 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Two Design Poems, colored markers. 1989, by JFH, MLR (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Poem for opening of Juana Alicia Mural in the Mission District, late 80's. "Solar Song for the Jubilant Blossom Murals of the Varrio Neighborhoods. mid-80's. w/edits. (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Poem. JFH. "90's Mobile" written in Iowa City, 1989-90. (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Draft: New ideas for dissertation - 1-2-90 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Prison Journal -4-90 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Manuscript: Universe at the Speed of Light: 50 sequences. Miniature book. 15 pages left. 4/90. Handwritten. JFH. (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - MFA - Blowfish - May 1990 [signed Master's Thesis, University of Iowa] (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - No Jacket / Sin Chaketa 7-5-90 (draft) (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Old Jacket - 1990 [Old Jacket/Sin Chaketa draft 8/6/90] (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Give Me Rainbow. 1 p. Handwritten on Gold's Gym flyer. 10/10/90. (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Mascaras de carne de Lumbre. 10/14/90. Words., Notes & Drawings. Pocket Sketch Pad. 60 pp. (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Candles.10 pp. 10/22/90. (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Klee Spider. (two versions). 10/30/90. (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Acts of (Re) Possession: Introduction - 10 - 90 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - A Possible Dali Television, 10 pp. 10/ 90. (Box 13, Folder 8)